## **JEVON WATSON**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Perth, Western Australia

+61 468 791 549

jevcwatson@gmail.com

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a software developer based in Western Australia. My career thus far has seen me focused on front end web application development. I have experience in a variety of programming languages and frameworks and possess a continuous desire to learn and improvemy skill set.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Coders for Causes - Full Stack Developer Jun 2021 - Nov 2021

Coders for Causes is a university club at the University of Western Australia that develops technical solutions for charities and non-profit organisations.

Over the course of several months in mid-late 2021 I volunteered as a full stack developer for the Coders For Causes winter project in collaboration with the Western Australia Institute of Sport. My role primarily involved using the Python Django REST framework to develop API end points to serve data to a VueJS frontend. This was my first experience working in a larger development team and using some of the fundamental agile development practises.

#### IBM - Application Developer

Jul 2021 - Present

I entered IBM in 2021. During this time I worked with a small agile development team to deliver an internal web based tool for use by one of IBMs clients. This project exposed me to the JavaScript framework Angular for the first time. I was able to produce various front end features and worked actively to fix defects and bugs documented by the testing team. Throughout the several months I spent as an intern during 2021 I made a point to take on board as much information and feedback as possible to improve not only my technical skills but also my professional, and social skills.

In 2022 i returned to IBM to continue in their graduate program. During my time as a graduate i maintained my position at the same client, but moved onto another internal project. This specific project gave me the opportunity to work with the Python programming language on an Azure Databricks instance to optimise and refactor an existing codebase. At the end of my time on the project we had delivered results that ultimately satisfied the clients requirements for the project

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Azure Fundamentals AZ-900

I achieved the Azure Fundamentals Certification in August of 2022

# Azure Developer Associate AZ-204

Presently working towards completing the AZ-204 certification

### **EXPERTISE**

- Various frontend development frameworks including VueJS, Angular, and React
- Backend web development using Python and Django / Django REST framework
- Interpersonal relationship building
- •Flexible and adaptive, Both technically and socially
- •Desire to continuously learn and improve existing skill se

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Edith Cowan University**

Bachelor of Computer Science **2019 - 2021**